Teachers Union of the City of New York Records 5015
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Teachers Union of the City of New York Records
1916-1965
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Teachers Union of the City of New York
5015
49.22 cubic feet
48.7 linear ft.
Records (documents).
Organization with a long history of radical involvement. Substantial materials on the Lusk Commission, teachers dismissals for unpopular political views during the 1950's, etc.
3338454
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, October 31, 2012
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, October 28, 2016
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5015 AV: Teachers Union of the City of New York Audio-Visual Materials 5015 MB: Teachers Union of the City of New York SCMWA Local 555 Anne Grant Pin Memorabilia 5015 mf: Teachers Union of the City of New York Executive Board Minutes on Microfilm 5018: US Congressional Investigation of Teachers' Union Local No. 555, United Public Workers of America, CIO 5019: AFT Executive Council Transcript of Hearing of Local 5 5020: AFT Executive Council Transcript of Hearing of Local 537 5445: Teachers Union of the City of New York Records 5470: Papers regarding Abraham Feingold's Prosecution For Alleged Communist Sympathies 5927: Teachers Union of the City of New York Additional Records 6046: Archives Union File (AUF)
Teachers' unions -- New York (State) -- New York -- Sources; Communist Party of the United States of America; National Association for the Advancement of Colored People; National Education Association of the United States; New York (N.Y.). Board of Education.; New York (N.Y.). City Council.; New York (State). Department of Education; New York (State). Legislature. Assembly.; Teachers' Union of the City of New York; United States. Congress. House. Committee on Internal Security.; United States. Congress. House. Committee on Un-American Activities.; United States. Congress. House. Special Committee on Un-American Activities (1938-1944); Abrams, Leonna.; Allen, James E., 1911-; Bailey, Forest; Chalmers, Allan Knight, 1897-; Dewey, Thomas E. (Thomas Edmund), 1902-1971.; Dodd, Bella V., 1904-1969; Dodson, Dan; Donegan, W. B.; Du Bois, W. E. B. (William Edward Burghardt), 1868-1963; Einstein, Albert, 1879-1955; Eisenhower, Dwight D. (Dwight David), 1890-1969; Essex, Martin; Flaxer, Abram, 1904-; Galamison, Milton A. (Milton Arthur), 1923-1988; Gross, Calvin; Harriman, W. Averell (William Averell), 1891-1986; Hughes, Langston, 1902-1967; Issacs, Stanley; Jackson, Ella; Jackson, Eugene; Javits, Jacob K. (Jacob Koppel), 1904-1986; Lamont, Corliss, 1902-1995; Leaderman, Abraham; Lefkowitz, Abraham, 1884-1956; Marcantonio, Vito, d 1902-1954; Moritt, Fred; Rockefeller, Nelson A. (Nelson Aldrich), 1908-1979; Russell, Rose; Schultz, Benjamin; Scott, W. J.; Wallach, Samuel; Wilkins, Roy, 1901-1981; Worley, James
3338454
- Academic Freedom, Arthur Aaron Case, Academic, 1951-1952 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  Memo, case, news clippings, press release, program correspondence, stencil, petition
- Academic Freedom, Harry Adler & Minerva Feinstein vs. Board of Education (Suit for Back Pay), 1960-1961 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Summons, press release, correspondence, news clippings
- Academic Freedom, Irving Adler, 1952-1955 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  A reply, press release, news clippings, interview questioning, legal papers, correspondence, form letters, testimonial dinner program
- Academic Freedom, American Association of University Professors, 1956-1958 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Resolutions, reprint, pamphlet (In Honor of Ralph E. Hinstead, General Secretary of A.A.U.P.), news clippings, correspondence, press release
- Academic Freedom, American Federation of Teachers Case of John Granbury, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  Explanation, correspondence, memo, Declaration of position
- Academic Freedom, American Library Association, 1948-1953 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  Release, news clippings, correspondence, post car
- Academic Freedom, Appeals to Commissioner, 1954-1955 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Appeals cases, correspondence, form letters, memo
- Academic Freedom, Articles and statements (printed), 1949-1959 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  News clippings, publications, pamphlet, reprints
- Academic Freedom, Articles and statements, 1949-1960 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  Fact sheet, statements, reprints, articles, addresses, comments, speeches, correspondence, editorial
- Academic Freedom, Association of American University, 1950-1953 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  News clippings, press release, correspondence, editorial, pamphlet
- Academic Freedom, Auerback, Leo, 1953-1955 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  Case, Exceptions to Report, Interview, correspondence
- Academic Freedom, Banning, 1919-1935 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  Report, form letter, fact sheet, leaflets, pamphlets
- Academic Freedom, Ben Baronofsky, 1953-1954 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  Correspondence, form letters, interviews, cases, statements, press release
- Academic Freedom, Bigotry & Bias in the Public Schools plus miscellaneous material, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  News clippings, draft of memo, press release, correspondence, bulletin, reports
- Academic Freedom, Bigotry & Bias in N.Y.C. Public Schools, 1951-1952 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  News clippings, press releases, correspondence, memo
- Academic Freedom, Bigotry & Bias & Prejudice in Textbooks, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  Correspondence, quotations, text list, bulletin, pamphlets, press release
- Academic Freedom, Bias & Bigotry in Textbooks, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  Publication, bulletin, correspondence, news clippings
- Academic Freedom, Dorothy Bloch, 1951-1953 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  Correspondence, press release, remarks, telegram
- Academic Freedom, Appeals to Commissioner, Dorothy Bloch, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  Case (Appeal), Dismissal
- Academic Freedom, Board of Education (General), 1948-1950 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  Telegram, press release, resolution, correspondence multicopy publication
- Academic Freedom, Budget Statements, 1962-1963 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  Statements, news clippings
- Academic Freedom, California Cases, 1951-1954 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  Correspondence, Appeal, memorandum, opinion
- Academic Freedom, California, Congressional Investigations, 1959-1961 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  Injunction suits, case, statement, expressions of opposition, fact sheet, publications, resolution correspondence, press releases, editorial, news clippings; Academic Freedom Campaign See: Feinberg Law
- Academic Freedom, Carneigie Hall meeting (June 3), 1949 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  Correspondence, form letters, leaflets, press releases, news clipping, excerpts from speeches
- Academic Freedom, Carnegie Hall meeting (June 2), 1950 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  Program, tickets, announcements, press release, statement, speech, address, remarks
- Academic Freedom, Censorship (Banning books, bullentin), 1947-1963 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  News clippings, press releases, bulletins, book list, pamphlets, photocopy, form letter, reprint
- Academic Freedom, Churches, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  Press release, correspondence, leaflet, president message, news clippings
- Academic Freedom, Civil Liberties Educational Foundation, 1962-1963 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  News clippings, correspondence, circular, issues of a newspaper
- Academic Freedom, Colleges, 1949-1960 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  News clippings, releases, bulletins, program, correspondence, resolution, statement, pamphlet, reprint
- Academic Freedom, Henry Steele Commager, 1949-1955 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  Correspondence, news clippings, reprint
- Academic Freedom, Committee, Erika Mann Meeting, 1938-1939 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  Correspondence, leaflet, form letter
- Academic Freedom, Committee, Mass Meeting, "Democracy in the Schools", 1938 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  Telegrams, press releases, questionnaire, correspondence, statement
- Academic Freedom, Committee, Progressive Educational Association, 1934-1935 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  Correspondence
- Academic Freedom, Committee letters and answers, eligibility of school teachers to membership in unions, 1938 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  Letters and answers (Questionnaires), correspondence List (for and against unions)
- Academic Freedom, Committee Meeting, 1938 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  Correspondence, bulletin
- Academic Freedom, Committee (Pamphlet on Academic Freedom, 1920), 1920-1921 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Academic Freedom, Issue of Communists in the School, 1949-1950 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  Publications, news clippings, press release, address note
- Academic Freedom, Correspondence, 1948-1954 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  Correspondence, pamphlet, form letters
- Academic Freedom, James Council, 1962-1963 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  Memos, correspondence, form letters, news clippings report, meeting notice
- Academic Freedom, Ruth Elizabeth Crawford, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  Correspondence, reprint
- Academic Freedom, Henry Danielowitz, 1953-1955 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  Press release, news clipping, memo, interviews, statement, correspondence
- Academic Freedom, Jerome Davis, speaker, 1950-1951 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Academic Freedom, Judge Hubert T. Delany, 1956-1961 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  Memo, news clippings, correspondence, biographical sketch
- Academic Freedom, Detroit, Elinor Maki, 1952-1953 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  Correspondence, news clippings
- Academic Freedom, Disclaimer Oath, 1962-1963 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  Correspondence, disclaimer oath
- Academic Freedom, Dismissals - Section 903, 1952-1953 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  Statement, correspondence, telegrams, press releases, reports, program, form letters
- Academic Freedom, Dismissals - Section 903, Correspondence (miscelleanous}, 1952-1956 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  Summary, statements, press releases, telegrams, form letters, correspondence, case
- Academic Freedom, Dismissals - Section 903, Action and support of other organizations and individuals, 1956-1960 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  Press release, memo, form letter
- Academic Freedom, Dismissals - Section 903, American Civil Liberties Union, Summary of Litigation, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  Summary
- Academic Freedom, Dismissals - Section 903, Appeal for re-hearing, 1954 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  Correspondence, bill, appeal for re-hearing, response to appeal, form letter
- Academic Freedom, Dismissals - Section 903, clipping, 1948-1957 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Academic Freedom, Dismissals - Section 903, miscellaneous clippings, 1952-1953 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  Correspondence, news clippings, news release, editorial, journal
- Academic Freedom, Dismissals - Section 903, Individuals dismissed by Board of Education, 1952 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  Dismissal list, card, program, correspondence, form letters
- Academic Freedom, Dismissals - Section 903, individuals dismissed by Board of Higher Education, 1952-1953 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  Form letters, correspondence, statements, press releases, reprint from Science, N.Y. Law Journal
- Academic Freedom, Dismissals - Section 903, Legal action, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  Correspondence, petition for writ to N.Y. State
- Academic Freedom, Dismissals - Section 903, Legal action - Appellate Division, 1952-1953 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  Telegram, press releases, news clippings, reports, cases, correspondence, reply, brief, notes, publication, bill
- Academic Freedom, Dismissals - Section 903, Legal action - Court of Appeals, 1954-1956 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  Notice of motion to Court of Appeals, Briefs to Court of Appeals, correspondence, form letter, press release, news clippings, list, pamphlet containing opinions of Justices
- Academic Freedom, Dismissals - Section 903, Legal Action - Printed Briefs, 1952-1953 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  Correspondence, Supreme Court Briefs
- Academic Freedom, Dismissals - Section 903 Legal Action - Public Education Association, 1952-1954 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  Correspondence, news clippings, brief to Court of Appeals
- Academic Freedom, Dismissals - Section 903, Legal Action, State Supreme Court, 1952-1953 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  Legal statement, press releases, correspondence, cases, news clipping, notice of application, petition
- Academic Freedom, Dismissals - Section 903 Legal Action - State Supreme Court N.Y. County, 1952 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  Notice of Application
- Academic Freedom, Dismissals - Section 903 Legal Action - State Supreme Court, Special term, 1952 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  The New York Law Journal, Clippings
- Academic Freedom, Dismissals - Section 903. U. S. Supreme Court, 1954-1955 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  Correspondence, news clipping, form letter
- Academic Freedom, Dismissals - Section 903, Legal - Supreme Court of U.S., 1954-1956 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  Petition for rehearing, Motion for Leave, Brief in opposition to dismiss
- Academic Freedom, Dismissals - Section 903, Legal Action - Supreme Court of U.S., 1956 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  Statement, news clipping, weekly bulletin
- Academic Freedom, Dismissals - Section 903, Legal action - U.S. Supreme Court, 1953-1954 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  Briefs, Motion to Dismiss Appeal, Jurisdictional statement, Notice of Appeal
- Academic Freedom, Dismissals - Section 903 Legal Action - Witt 4 Cramer, correspondence, 1952-1953 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  Correspondence, press releases, proposed stipulation
- Academic Freedom, Dismissals - Section 903, Teachers Union Action, 1952-1956 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  Broadside, pamphlet, editorial, news clipping, open letter, briefs, reports, resolution, reprints, form letter, notice of application
- Academic Freedom, Dismissals - Section 903 Questionnaire, Data on dismissal, 1952-1956 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  Questionnaires, sheets of data on dismissal, form letters, correspondence
- Academic Freedom, Dismissals - Section 903, Replies from educations to Slochower ruling questionnaire, 1956 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  Photocopy, correspondence, form letters, press release, list of "903" signers
- Academic Freedom, Dismissals - Section 903, Teachers dismissed, 1952-1954 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  Telegrams, news clippings, correspondence, form letters, press releases, reports, broadside
- Academic Freedom, Dismissals - Section 903, Stipulants, 1956-1958 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  Photocopy, briefs, correspondence, form letters, memo, weekly bulletin, appeals
- Academic Freedom, Dismissals - Section 903, Action for Damages, 1957-1959 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  Receipt, news clipping, form letter, report, correspondence, N.Y. Court of Appeals opinion, brief, memo, cases, photocopy
- Academic Freedom, Dismissals - Section 903, Warren Austin, 1957-1959 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  Briefs, news clippings, Journal, photocopy, correspondence, memo, report, appeal
- Academic Freedom, Dismissals - Section 903, Paxton Blair, 1952-1955 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  Press release, correspondence, receipt, legal report, list of persons receiving brief
- Academic Freedom, Dismissals - Section 903, Joseph Bressler, 1956 (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Academic Freedom, Dismissals - Section 903 Edwin Berry Burgum, 1952 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  Form letters, correspondence, pamphlet
- Academic Freedom, Dismissals - Section 903, Ephraim Cross, 1949-1956 (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Academic Freedom, Dismissals - Section 903 Terry Rosenbaum, 1954 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  Form letters, pamphlet
- Academic Freedom, Dismissals - Section 903 Rosenbaum & Gilgoff, 1951-1954 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  Pamphlet, broadside, press release, news clippings, photocopy, statements, resolutions, form letters, correspondence, post cart, invitations, reports, hearing
- Academic Freedom, Dismissals - Section 903 Morris Seltzer, 1947-1952 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  Form letters, correspondence
- Academic Freedom, Dismissals - Section 903 Mrs. Bertha Singer, 1953-1954 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  Report of interview, correspondence, news clippings
- Academic Freedom, Dismissals - Section 903 Harry Slochower, Briefs, 1954-1955 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  Briefs, notice of motion
- Academic Freedom, Dismissals - Section 903 Slochower Loans, 1952-1957 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  Invoice, correspondence, press clippings, briefs, legal report, statement, form letter
- Academic Freedom, Dismissals - Section 903 Harry Slochower, 1955-1958 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  Periodical, report, open letter, correspondence, bills for printing legal expenses, news clippings, form letters
- Academic Freedom, Dismissals - Section 903 Margaret Spahr, 1952-1955 (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Academic Freedom, Dismissals - Section 903 Isaac A. Sperber, 1953-1954 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  Statement, interview, correspondence, form letter, briefs, broadside, notice of pleading
- Academic Freedom, Dismissals - Section 903 Dudley David Straus, 1955 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  News clippings, reports, statement, briefs, memo, correspondence, interview, form letter
- Academic Freedom, Douglas & Black (Supreme Court Justices), 1951-1953 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  Correspondence, resolution, address, appeal, leaflet, news clippings
- Academic Freedom, Emergency Civil Liberties Committee, 1954-1962 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  Resolution, release, receipt, news clippings, list of signers, announcement, leaflets correspondence, speech, reprints
- Academic Freedom, Charles Eckstat, 1953 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  Correspondence, statement, clippings
- Academic Freedom, Stella Eliashow, 1927-1953 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  Bulletin, entire record, reports, release, statement, interviews, Christmas cards, case, evaluations, correspondence, form letters
- Academic Freedom, Albert Einstein, 1953-1955 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  Correspondence, photocopy, press release, leaflet, publication, news clippings, periodical
- Academic Freedom, Estrin Article "The Controversial Issue: A Re-examination", 1952-1953 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  Publication, press release, bulletins, correspondence reprints, form letter
- Academic Freedom, Howard Fast, 1954 (Box 8, Folder 4)
- Academic Freedom, Fear, 1952-1955 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  Press release, address, correspondence, news clippings form letter
- Academic Freedom, Feinberg Law, 1949 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  Form letters, leaflet, broadsides, announcement, resolution
- Academic Freedom, Feinberg Law, 1949-1952 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  History and analysis, survey and report, correspondence, memo, appeal, form letters
- Academic Freedom, Minna Finkelstein, 1942-1954 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  News clipping, interviews, case, legal paper, rating reports, correspondence, statement
- Academic Freedom, Ruth & Jeannette Finkelstein, 1952-1954 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  Press release, correspondence, form letters, exceptions to report
- Academic Freedom, Mildred Flacks, 1947-1955 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  Photocopy, correspondence, form letters, record of service, statements, page of a transcript, interview, leaflet
- Academic Freedom, Fletcher, Eudora (Needleman), 1949-1950 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  Form letters, leaflet, telegrams, correspondence
- Academic Freedom, Foner Case, 1948 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  Printed case, correspondence, news clipping
- Academic Freedom, William Frauenglass, 1953 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  Correspondence, form letters, profiles, statements, news clippings, notices
- Academic Freedom, Freedom in the Schools, Rally-City Center Casino, 1952 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  Report, press release, bulletins, postcards, addresses, pamphlet, correspondence, speeches, license, broadside
- Academic Freedom, Freedom Fund, 1948-1950 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  Correspondence, form letters, leaflets, notices, broadsides
- Academic Freedom, Freedom Fund, 1951-1954 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  Pledge cards, records, correspondence, form letter collection sheets, announcements, bulletins
- Academic Freedom, Buell G. Gallagher, 1952-1955 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  Correspondence, form letters, reprint, speech, news clippings, note, pamphlets, hearing
- Academic Freedom, General, 1948-1962 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  Resolution, telegram, news clippings, leaflet, release, correspondence, form letters
- Academic Freedom, General, 1948-1950 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  Resolution, news release, correspondence, telegram, form letter, leaflets
- Academic Freedom, General, 1950-1953 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  News clippings, correspondence, excerpts from debate
- Academic Freedom, General, 1951-1952 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  Correspondence, form letters, announcements, weekly press release, bulletins, fact sheet, reprint
- Academic Freedom, General, Hartley Investigation, 1948-1949 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  Announcement, correspondence, press releases, statement, publications, bulletins, reports, news clipping, broadside, reprints
- Academic Freedom, General, Legal, 1956-1962 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  Brief, correspondence, newspaper, news clippings
- Academic Freedom, Cyril Graze, 1951-1953 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  Leaflets, news clippings, open letter, statements, press releases, excerpts, correspondence
- Academic Freedom, Mildred Grossman, 1952-1954 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  Case, legal letter, interview, exceptions to report, correspondence, memo, form letters, appeal
- Academic Freedom, Minnie Gutride, personal, 1948-1949 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  Correspondence, telegram
- Academic Freedom, Minnie Gutride, Replies ( Individuals ), 1948-1949 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  Correspondence, resolution, legal paper
- Academic Freedom, Minnie Gutride, Replies (Notables), 1948-1949 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  Correspondence, press release
- Academic Freedom, Minnie Gutride, Replies (Organizations), 1948-1949 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  Correspondence, telegram, press release, report
- Academic Freedom, Minnie Gutride, T.U. press statements and clippings, 1948-1949 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  Press release, memo, press clippings, correspondence form letter, fact sheet
- Academic Freedom, Hartley Committee Investigations Clippings, 1948 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  News clippings
- Academic Freedom, Hartley Committee Investigation, 1948 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  Correspondence, resolution, telegrams
- Academic Freedom, Hartley Committee Investigation of T.U., 1948 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  Interim report, transcripts, resolutions, statement fact sheet, press releases, correspondence, form letters
- Academic Freedom, Hartley Investigation, Hearings, 1948 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  Excerpts from testimony, volume of hearings
- Academic Freedom, Hartley Investigation, Materials Used, 1947-1948 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  Telegrams, correspondence, photocopies of correspondence
- Academic Freedom, Philip Horowitz, 1952-1953 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  Bulletin, fact sheet, interviews, brief, appeal
- Academic Freedom, Robert M. Hutchins, 1954-1955 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  Press releases, telegrams, news clippings, leaflet correspondence, memo, remarks, reprint
- Academic Freedom, Individuals (A-Z), 1947-1956 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  Statements, telegrams, interview, form letters, correspondence, open letters, article, notices
- Academic Freedom, Individuals, 1961-1962 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  Interview, statement, correspondence, news clippings
- Academic Freedom, Jaffe Case, 1943-1949 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  Correspondence, press releases, telegrams, memo, case, itemized listing, statement, observation report
- Academic Freedom, Jaffe Case, 1948-1949 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  News clipping, briefs, bulletins, correspondence, form letters, cases, hearing, press release, report, reprint
- Academic Freedom, Jansen Resolution, 1949-1952 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  Findings of Fact & Declaration of Policy, press release, receipt, telegrams, news clippings, minutes, resolution, reports, correspondence, form letters
- Academic Freedom, Jansen Eesolution, Declaration of Policy, 1951-1952 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  Press release, statement, analysis, news clipping telegram, addresses
- Academic Freedom, Jansen Resolution, 1951-1952 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  Newspaper clippings, journals
- Academic Freedom, Jenner Commission Hearings, 1921-1934 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  Publications